A Guide to the Governor Mark R. Warner, Virginia Liaison Office, Records, 2002-2005
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Mark R. Warner, Virginia Liaison Office, Records 2002-2005
The Library of Virginia
42629
0.53 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, transferred on 7 April 2006
Historical Information
The General Assembly established the Virginia Liaison Office in 1978 (Chapter 505, 1978 Acts) to be an institutional link between state and federal government as well as Virginia and other states. This office is under the jurisdiction of the Virginia Office of the Governor.
The Virginia Liaison Office promotes Virginia's interests with the federal government. Staff included Jan B. Faircloth, Director; Eileen Filler-Corn, Deputy Director; Patrice Taylor, Special Assistant for Research; and Josh Cohn, Special Assistant.
Scope and Content
The Governor Mark R. Warner, Virginia Liaison Office, Records are housed in 2 boxes. The collection consists of correspondence, miscellaneous records, on-site visits/conferences and reports.
The correspondence consists of constituent correspondence and the National Governors' Association mailed to the Virginia Liaison Office. The constituent correspondence were forwarded to Constituent Services office and are arranged in reverse chronological order. The National Governors' Association letters are arranged in chronological order and contain primarily congratulatory letters and invitations.
Other records include a request for the Virginia Liaison Office to aid Hampton Roads in funding match money for tunnel and fire safety equipment (November 2005); notes and handouts from the Virginia Commission on Military Bases (VCOMB) visit to the Norfolk Naval Shipyard (December 2004); notes and handouts from the Accelerating Innovation Conference (October 2005) and copies of Federal Mandate Reports from 2002 to 2005.
Contents List
- Correspondence - Letters
  - Bob Dole to Governor Warner (re: World War II Memorial), April 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clinton O. Lucas, Jr., Mayor of Shenandoah, to Governor Warner (re: HR 2941/Brownfields Redevelopment Enhancement Act of 2001), July 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Governor Mike Johanns to Jan Faircloth (re: drought), August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters (re: J.Davis/HR 1213 Greenwood Interstate Waste Bill), May-August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rep. Wally Herger to Governor Warner (re: Unemployment Compensation), August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Governor Warner to President George W. Bush (re: Request to the President to declare a major disaster for the Commonwealth of Virginia as a result of flash flooding from the storms in Southwestern Virginia on November 18th and 19th, 2003), November 26, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Maryland Transit Administration letter to MARC Train Service Passengers (re: passenger awareness following the Madrid train bombings), March 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bruce F. Jamerson to Jan Faircloth (re: HJR 118), 27 May 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jan Faircloth to Tommy G. Thompson (re: HJR 118), 8 June 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters and information on Jan Faircloth's involvement with Agriculture and Forestry Action Team under Michael J. Schewel, April-June 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Constituent Correspondence
  - 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - National Governors' Association
  - 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous
  - Request from Congressman Bobby Scott, through the Virginia Liaison Office, for the Commonwealth of Virginia to aid Hampton Roads in funding "match" money to receive grants through the Federal Transportation Bill for tunnel and fire safety equipment (November 2005) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Summary of S346 and HR 1829 Re: Federal Prison Industries Competition in Contracting Act of 2003. A letter from Gary P. Held (Director of Change Management for Delco Remy International) to Secretary Michael Schewel Re: Federal Prison Industries Competition in Contracting Act of 2003 (November 2003) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- On-Site Visit/Conferences
  - Notes and handouts from the Virginia Commission on Military Bases (VCOMB) visit to the Norfolk Naval Shipyard (December 2004) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notes and handouts from the Accelerating Innovation Conference (October 2005) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Reports
  - Federal Mandate Report, 2002-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)